Preliminary Inventory to the S. Herbert Frankel Papers, 1887-1975
Hoover Institution Archives
S. Herbert Frankel Papers,
1887-1975
78109
Frankel, S. Herbert (Sally Herbert), 1903-
88 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 oversize folder. (37 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, correspondence, statistics, reports, memoranda, notes, and commission proceedings, relating to economic conditions, finance, agriculture, mining, and transportation in South Africa, Rhodesia, and East Africa.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Biographical/Historical Note
British economist; economic adviser to South African and Southern Rhodesian governments, 1941-1958.
Access Points
Agriculture--Africa, East.; Agriculture--South Africa.; Finance--South Africa.; Gold mines and mining--South Africa.; Mines and mineral resources--Zambia.; Mines and mineral resources--Zimbabwe.; National income--South Africa.; Railroads--Zambia.; Railroads--Zimbabwe.; Transportation--South Africa.; Africa.; Africa, East.; Africa, East--Economic conditions.; South Africa.; South Africa--Economic conditions.; Zambia.; Zambia--Economic conditions.; Zimbabwe.; Zimbabwe--Economic conditions.
Container List
- Research Material for Maize Book, Co-operation in Africa, Sugar Research, Memoranda, and Correspondence, 1
- Typed MS of Railway Book, 2
- Press Clipping, RE: Railway Policy of South Africa
- Tariff Act 1925 - Amended 1926
- Railway Rates, Commission, Figures
- Johannesburg Town Plan 1934
- Census Report on Transportation Workers, 1933
- Railway Notes and Correspondence, 3
- MS of Railway Book, Charts and Rates, 4
- CSAR General Administration Folders, Mercantiles Conference, Rates, Railage on Coal, 5
- Distribution Costs Memorandum and Evidence, 1944, 6
- National Income - Southern Rhodesia
- Railway & Harbours Working & Finance
- Customs Tariff Commission
- Correspondence RE: Coming of Age - Maskew Miller
- Commission of Inquiry into Municipal Passenger Transport System, Power Station & Workshops - Johannesburg
- The Low Grade Ore/Mines Commission Evidence, 7
- 1932-45 - National Income of South Africa, 8-10
- 1932-45 - National Income of South Africa - Draft of unpublished Book, 11
- 1932-45 - National Income of South Africa - Tables, 12
- Memo on the Concept of National Income & its Calculation in South Africa, 13
- Correspondence on same
- Reports on Same
- Preliminary International Comparison of National Products & Internal Purchasing Power of Currencies - 1953
- Various National Income Reports - Australia and Europe pre-war
- Memo on the Sources of Information on African Social & Economic Condition by Dr. C. Leubuscher, 14
- Economic Development of South Africa Information, 15
- Gold Mining Articles
- Capital Investment in Africa - Preliminary Survey, 16
- Notes, Maps and Correspondence (esp. RE: Gold Mining)
- Capital Investment in Africa - Research Papers, 17
- Correspondence RE: Gold Mining Investigation
- South African Institute of International Affairs - Source Material - 5/1946, 18
- South African Institute of International Affairs - Source Material - 5/1946 - Reports, 19
- 1938 Commonwealth Conference - Australia, 20-21
- 1938-45 - Financial & Economic Memoranda for South Africa, 22
- South African Treasury Advisory Council on Economic & Financial Policy 1941-45 (Frankel Economic Advisor to JH Hofmeyr), 23
- 1941-42 - Union of South Africa Miner's Phtisis Commission, 24
- 1941-42 - Union of South Africa Miner's Phtisis Commission - Minutes, 25
- 1941-42 - Union of South Africa Miner's Phtisis Commission - Unpublished Minutes, 26
- Rhodesian Railway Commission: Interim Report 1943, Part I, 27
- Rhodesian Railway Commission: Interim Report 1943, Part II -, 28; oversized
- Rhodesian Railway Commission, 29
- Rhodesian Railway Commission - Enquiry, 30-32
- Rhodesian Railway Commission - Enquiry - Record of Proceedings, 33-34
- 1946 - Unpublished Report on Kenya - Future Economic Policy, etc., 35
- Political Economy of Gold Coast and Ghana 1969 - Stephen Hymer
- Gold Coast Mine Labour Reports - 1948
- 1947 Visit to Gold Coast - Correspondence and Reports
- 1948-51 - Overseas Food Corporation
- Report on the Groundnut Mission/Scheme - East & Central Africa, 36-37
- East Africa Royal Commission - 1953-55, 38
  - Land Tenure
  - Race Relations, 39
  - Reports
  - Politics
  - Misc. Reports (Cotton Industry, Food Staples, Economy, etc.), 40
  - Economics, by country, 41
  - Marketing & Distribution
  - Capital Investment & Financial Policies
  - Credit
  - Industries
  - Notes of Meetings & Visits, 42-43
  - Miscellaneous Reports, 44
  - Uganda Development Corp. Ltd., 45
  - Miscellaneous Reports, 46
  - Miscellaneous Reports, 47
  - Southern Province Report -, 48; 2 copies
    - Drafts
    - Correspondence
  - Drafts of chapters for Report, 49
  - District plans, memoranda, reports, notes:, 50
    - Uganda
    - Tanganyika
    - East Africa
    - Kenya, 51
  - South Rhodesia: Urban African Affairs Commission
    - Evidence & Statistical Material, 52-53
    - Reports, legislation, setting up the commission, 54
    - Notes & drafts by consultants, 55
    - Notes on Urbanization
    - Replies to questionnaires
    - Authority documents
- "The Return to Capital in the South African Gold Mining Industry, 1887-1965", 56
  - Correspondence, 57
  - Oxford Calculations - COHORT, 58
  - Data, Reports, Notes, 59-60
  - Statistics, 61-69
  - Transvaal Chamber of Mines Statements to Mining Industry Board, 70
  - Gold Producers' Committee Statements
  - Revised Study - Bound
  - Unpublished Tables, 71-74
- 1946-71 Oxford Lectures on Economic Development Policy, and Notes, 75
- Official & Personal Correspondence, 1925-75, 76-86
  (box #79 is correspondence of Sally Frankel)
- Public Lectures, Addresses and Articles, etc., 87
- Capital investments in Africa - Statistics, Stock Quotes, etc., 88-89